<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>AlgoSphere</title>
        <link>https://rathink4.github.io/</link>
        <description>AlgoSphere</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://rathink4.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>A Quick Intro to Terraform</title>
    <link>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/intro-to-terraform/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><guid>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/intro-to-terraform/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is Terraform and Why you want IaC? Terraform an infrastructure as code tool (written in Go) that can provision resources in the cloud from simple declarative code. When building an app in the cloud, you may find yourself using the graphical user interface (GUI) of your preferred Cloud Service Provider, clicking buttons and paying for products just like you would on an e-commerce website. But the only drawback of this approach is that it&rsquo;s complete and total chaos when you might click thousands of different buttons to get you Virtual machine (VM) configured properly.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Spark and its impact on AWS and Databricks: Empowering Big Data Solutions</title>
    <link>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/spark_aws_databricks/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><guid>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/spark_aws_databricks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the ever-evolving landscape of big data processing and analytics, Apache Spark has emerged as a powerful open-source framework, revolutionizing how organizations manage and analyze massive datasets. Its seamless integration with cloud platforms like Amazon Web Services (AWS) and specialized platforms like Databricks has further accelerated its adoption and transformed the data analytics landscape. In this blog post, we&rsquo;ll explore Spark&rsquo;s influence on AWS technologies and Databricks, along with certifications that can help individuals deepen their understanding and expertise in these areas.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Demystifying Docker: A Beginner Guide to Containerization</title>
    <link>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/docker/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><guid>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/docker/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction: In the fast-paced world of software development, agility and scalability are key factors in delivering successful applications. Traditional methods of deploying applications on physical or virtual servers often come with challenges like dependency issues, environment inconsistencies, and deployment bottlenecks. However, with the rise of containerization technology, developers now have a powerful tool at their disposal to streamline the deployment process and enhance application portability. In this blog post, we&rsquo;ll delve into the world of Docker and containerization, exploring what they are, how they work, and why they&rsquo;re revolutionizing the way we build and deploy applications.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Beginner Guide to Hadoop: Unlocking the Power of Big Data</title>
    <link>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/hadoop/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><guid>https://rathink4.github.io/posts/hadoop/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is Hadoop? Hadoop is an open-source framework developed by the Apache Software Foundation, designed to store and process large datasets distributed across clusters of commodity hardware. It provides a scalable, reliable, and cost-effective solution for handling big data.
Components of Hadoop Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) At the core of Hadoop is the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS), a distributed file system that stores data across multiple machines in a Hadoop cluster.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
